Hale Family Papers, 1787-1988
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- HALE FAMILY
  - Generations V and VI
    - Diederich, Sybil (Hale) and Kurt [daughter and son-in-law of Arthur and Camilla (Connor) Hale]
      - General, 1900, undated (Box 107, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence to Hales, 1897-1907, undated (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Hale, Edward Everett III [son of Herbert Dudley and Margaret (Marquand) Hale]: letters to Ellen Day Hale [aunt], 1918-20 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Hale, Herbert Dudley, Jr. [son of Herbert Dudley and Margaret (Marquand) Hale]: General, 1901-09, 1916 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Hale, Laura (Hale) [daughter of Herbert Dudley and Margaret (Marquand) Hale]: letters to Ellen Day Hale, 1920-27 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Hale, Maurice Perkins [son of Edward Everett Hale, Jr. and Rose (Perkins) Hale]: letters to Hales, 1923, 1932, undated (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Hale, Nathan and Lillian (Boynton) [son and daughter-in-law of Edward Everett Hale, Jr. and Rose (Perkins) Hale] (Box 107)
      - General, 1947-86, undated (Box 107, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence
        - Nathan to Ellen Day Hale, 1917-18 (Box 107, Folder 8)
        - Lillian to Ellen Day Hale and Gabrielle Clements, 1935, 1949, undated (Box 107, Folder 9)
    - Hale, Nathan [son of Nathan and Lillian (Boynton) Hale]: clipping, 1976 (Box 107, Folder 10)
    - Hale, Robert Beverly ( -1985) [son of Herbert Dudley and Margaret (Marquand) Hale]
      - General, 1948-85 (Box 107, Folder 11)
      - Letters to Ellen Day Hale, 1934, undated (Box 107, Folder 12)
    - Hale, Thomas Shaw [son of Edward Everett Hale, Jr and Rose (Perkins) Hale]: letters to Ellen Day Hale, 1930-34 (Box 107, Folder 13)
    - Noble, Elsa (Diederich) [daughter of Sybil (Hale) Diederich]
      - Letters to Lilian (Westcott) Hale, Ellen Day Hale, and Gabrielle Clements, 1938, undated (Box 107, Folder 14)
      - Estate, 1972-78 (Box 107, Folder 15)
    - Thorne, Margaret (Hale) [daughter of Herbert Dudley and Margaret (Marquand) Hale]: correspondence
      - To Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) Hale, 1902-09 (Box 107, Folder 16)
      - To Ellen Day Hale and Gabrielle Clements, 1910-35 (Box 107, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified Hale Family fragments, undated (Box 107, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous papers
      - General, 1781-1916, undated (Box 107, Folder 19)
      - Composition (incomplete) on the first Battle of Bull Run (possibly a Westcott item), 1863 (Box 107, Folder 20)
      - Handmade newspaper The Herald, No. 5 and No. 7, 1813, undated (Box 107, Folder 21)
      - Japanese prints, undated (Box 107, Folder 22)
      - Liberty Loan Committee of New England postcard series, circa 1918 (Box 107, Folder 23)
      - Society for Propagating the Gospel Among Indians, and others, of North America: reports, 1795-98 (Box 107, Folder 24)
      - Typescript of journal of William Sydney Thayer (friend of Charles Hale), 1852-63 (Box 107, Folder 25)
      - Story by Rose Zeffler (friend of and model for Philip L. and Lilian W. Hale), circa 1913 (Box 107, Folder 26)
- BEECHER FAMILY
  - General and genealogy, undated (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1857, 1873(?) (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Beecher, Catharine E. to Harriet (Beecher) Stowe and Mary (Beecher) Perkins [sisters], undated (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Beecher, Charles to Ellen Day Hale [great niece], 1892 (Box 108, Folder 4)
- GILMAN FAMILY
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1836-1915, undated (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Gilman, Charlotte (Perkins)
    - Lecture flyer, undated (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence to Hales, 1885-1934 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Gilman, Frances: correspondence to Hales, 1896 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Gilman, Kate (Perkins)
    - Correspondence to Emily (Perkins) Hale [sister], 1873 (Box 108, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence to Mary (Beecher) Perkins [mother], 1857 (Box 108, Folder 10)
  - Gilman, Maria P.: correspondence to Emily (Perkins) Hale, 1900 (Box 108, Folder 11)
- HOOKER FAMILY
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1911 (Box 108, Folder 12)
  - Hooker, Isabella (Beecher)
    - Chicago World's Fair, 1893 (Box 108, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence
      - Emily (Perkins) Hale [niece], 1893-1902 (Box 108, Folder 14)
      - Harriet (Beecher) Stowe and Mary (Beecher) Perkins [sisters], 1857 (Box 108, Folder 15)
      - Lilian Westcott [Hale], [great niece], 1902 (Box 108, Folder 16)
  - Hooker, John: letters to Mary (Beecher) Perkins [sister-in-law], 1857 (Box 108, Folder 17)
  - Hooker, Mary: letters to Harriet (Beecher) Stowe [aunt], undated (Box 108, Folder 18)
- PERKINS FAMILY
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1852, 1907, undated (Box 108, Folder 19)
  - Perkins, Charles E. letters to Mary (Beecher) Perkins [mother], 1856-57 (Box 108, Folder 20)
  - Perkins, Frances to Emily (Perkins) Hale [sister-in-law], 1895 (Box 108, Folder 21)
  - Perkins, Frederick B.: correspondence
    - Ellen Day Hale [niece], 1872 (Box 108, Folder 22)
    - Mary (Beecher) Perkins [mother], 1856 (Box 108, Folder 23)
  - Perkins, Lucy: letters to Mary (Beecher) Perkins [mother], undated (Box 108, Folder 24)
  - Perkins, Mary (Beecher)
    - Notebook, 1827 (Box 108, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence
      - Emily (Perkins) Baldwin [sister-in-law], 1830-35, undated (Box 108, Folder 26)
      - Foote, Eliza [cousin?], 1844 (Box 108, Folder 27)
      - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) [son-in-law and daughter], undated (Box 108, Folder 28)
      - Hale, Ellen Day [granddaughter], 1862, undated (Box 108, Folder 29)
  - Perkins, Mary R.: letters to Emily (Perkins) Hale, 1899 (Box 108, Folder 30)
  - Perkins, Thomas Clap
    - Obituaries, 1872 (Box 108, Folder 31)
    - Letters to Ellen Day Hale [granddaughter], 1860, 1863 (Box 108, Folder 32)
- STOWE FAMILY
  - General, 1970, undated (Box 108, Folder 33)
  - Stowe, Eliza: letters to Emily (Perkins) Hale [cousin], 1898 (Box 108, Folder 34)
  - Stowe, Harriet (Beecher): letters to Ellen Day Hale [niece], 1889 (Box 108, Folder 35)
- EVERETT FAMILY
  - Generation I
    - Everett, Oliver (1752-1802): Humane Society of Massachusetts membership certificate, 1791 (Box 109, Folder 1)
      [See Oversize Materials]
    - Everett, Lucy (Hill) (1768-1824)
      - Correspondence
        - To Alexander Hill and Lucretia Orne (Peabody) Everett [son and daughter-in-law], 1816-21 (Box 109, Folder 2)
        - From Mrs. Torry, undated (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Generation II
    - Everett, Alexander Hill (1790-1847)
      - General, 1847-1981 (Box 109, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Batchelder, Samuel, 1808 (Box 109, Folder 5)
        - Eustis, William, 1816 (Box 109, Folder 6)
        - Everett, Edward [brother], 1822-26 (Box 109, Folder 7)
        - Everett, Enoch [brother], 1816 (Box 109, Folder 8)
        - Everett, Lucy (Hill) [mother], 1806-22 (Box 109, Folder 9-18)
        - Hale, Edward Everett [nephew], 1844-47 (Box 109, Folder 19)
        - Hale, Nathan, Sr. [brother-in-law], 1818-44 (Box 109, Folder 20)
        - Hale, Nathan, Jr. [nephew], 1841-42 (Box 110, Folder 1)
        - Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) [sister], 1811-47 (Box 110, Folder 2-10)
        - Hale, Sarah Everett and Susan [nieces], 1841-42 (Box 110, Folder 11)
        - Ward, Thomas W., 1844 (Box 110, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, incoming
        - Adams, John Quincy, 1808 (Box 110, Folder 13)
        - Batchelder, Samuel, 1808 (Box 110, Folder 14)
        - Drojat, Francois, 1826 (Box 110, Folder 15)
        - Forsyth, John, 1840 (Box 110, Folder 16)
        - Kennedy, J., 1840 (Box 110, Folder 17)
        - Slidell, Alexander, 1827 (Box 110, Folder 18)
      - Writings
        - Diary, 1838-39 (Box 110, Folder 19)
        - Financial records, 1846-50 (Box 110, Folder 20)
        - Manuscript "Ch. IV: First Settlement of Virginia continued," undated (Box 110, Folder 21)
    - Everett, Lucretia Orne (Peabody) (1786-1862)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Everett, Lucy (Hill) [mother-in-law], 1818-23 (Box 110, Folder 22)
        - Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) [sister-in-law]
          - 1816-46 (Box 110, Folder 23-30)
          - 1847-50 (Box 111, Folder 1)
          - ?, Lucia, 1823 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Everett, Edward (1794-1865)
      - General, 1834-1941 (Box 111, Folder 3)
      - "Address at the Consecration of the Cemetary at Gettysburg," 1853 (Box 111, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Everett, John [brother], undated (Box 111, Folder 5)
        - Hale, Charles [nephew], 1855 (Box 111, Folder 6)
        - Hale, Edward Everett [nephew], 1840-56 (Box 111, Folder 7)
        - Hale, Nathan, Sr. [brother-in-law], 1818-56 (Box 111, Folder 8)
        - Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) [sister], 1815-16, 1856 (Box 111, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, incoming: Tyler, John, 1843 (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - Everett, Charlotte (Brooks) (1800-1859): correspondence to Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) [sister-in-law], 1827, 1832 (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - Everett, John (1801-26)
      - General, 1826, undated (Box 111, Folder 12)
      - Financial, 1822 (Box 111, Folder 13)
      - Activities
        - Boston Debate Society, 1825 (Box 111, Folder 14)
        - Transylvania University, Professor of Greek, 1819-20 (Box 111, Folder 15)
        - Harvard Law School, 1823-25 (Box 111, Folder 16)
        - Law practice, 1823-24, undated (Box 111, Folder 17)
        - Political matters, undated (Box 111, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, outgoing
        - Bronson, Oliver, undated (Box 111, Folder 19)
        - [Durivage], Lucy (Everett) [sister], 1815? (Box 111, Folder 20)
        - Everett, Lucy (Hill) [mother], 1815?, 1819 (Box 111, Folder 21)
        - Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) and Nathan, Sr. [sister and brother-in-law], 1818-20 (Box 111, Folder 22)
        - Mellen, Grenville, 1820-25 (Box 111, Folder 23-26)
        - Miscellaneous, 1824-25, undated (Box 111, Folder 27)
      - Correspondence, incoming
        - Bronson, Oliver, 1821-25 (Box 111, Folder 28-31)
        - Elwyn, John L., 1824 (Box 112, Folder 1)
        - Lyman, Charles, 1819-21 (Box 112, Folder 2)
        - Walker, Charles, Jr., 1820-23 (Box 112, Folder 3-5)
        - Miscellaneous, 1822-24 (Box 112, Folder 6)
      - Writings
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 112, Folder 7)
        - On American literature and education, circa 1820 (Box 112, Folder 8)
        - Verses, circa 1819-20 (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - Durivage, Lucy (Everett) (1791-circa 1864): correspondence to Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) [sister], 1822?-51 (Box 112, Folder 10)
    - Everett, Oliver, Jr. (1788-1864): correspondence to Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) and Nathan, Sr. [sister and brother-in-law], 1827-43 (Box 112, Folder 11)
    - Everett, Ann (Gardner) (1784-1840): correspondence to Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) [sister-in-law], 1828-29 (Box 112, Folder 12)
    - Everett, Thomas
      - Correspondence
        - To family, 1816 (Box 112, Folder 13)
        - To Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) [sister], 1816, 1829, 1830 (Box 112, Folder 14)
  - Generation III
    - Buffum, Relief (Everett) (1814-1902): correspondence to Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett) [aunt], 1837 (Box 112, Folder 15)
    - Durivage, Francis Alexander (1814-81): correspondence to Hale, Nathan, Jr. [cousin], 1829 (Box 112, Folder 16)
    - Everett, William (1839-1910): correspondence to Hale, Edward Everett [cousin], 1888 (Box 112, Folder 17)
- HILL FAMILY
  - Hill, Alexander: correspondence from Sullivan, James, 1797 (Box 112, Folder 18)
- WESTCOTT FAMILY
  - General, 1873, undated (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Genealogy
    - General, 1931-34, undated (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - Stukeley Westcote and Some of His Descendants, circa 1890 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Westcott, Edward Gardner [father of Lilian (Westcott) Hale]
    - General, 1847-76 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - Death, 1898 (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - Lee Arms Company
      - General, 1894-97 (Box 113, Folder 6-7)
      - Correspondence re: sale of patents on guns
        - A-T, 1896-97 (Box 113, Folder 8-21)
        - W-Z, 1896-97 (Box 114, Folder 1-3)
  - Westcott, Harriet (Clarke) [mother of Lilian (Westcott) Hale]
    - General, 1931?, undated (Box 114, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous, 1888, undated (Box 114, Folder 5)
      - From Chase, William Merritt (re Lilian), 1898 (Box 114, Folder 6)
      - From Hale, Philip Leslie [son-in-law], undated (Box 114, Folder 7)
      - From Littell, Elton G. [son-in-law], 1912 (Box 114, Folder 8)
      - To ?, Julie, 1877 (Box 114, Folder 9)
    - Education, Ingham University, LeRoy, NY
      - Catalogs, 1869-72 (Box 114, Folder 10)
      - Compositions, 1868-69 (Box 114, Folder 11)
  - Westcott, Mary Dent [sister of Lilian (Westcott) Hale]
    - General, 1882-86 (Box 114, Folder 12)
    - Bible, 1885 (Box 114)
- BASSET/CLARKE FAMILY
  - General, 1896, 1952 (Box 114, Folder 13)
  - Mary (Basset) Clarke [mother of Harriet (Clarke) Westcott]
    - Hymnbook, 1845 (Box 114)
    - Watercolors, undated (Box 114, Folder 14)
- LITTELL FAMILY
  - Littell, Anna (Westcott) [sister of Lilian (Westcott) Hale] and Elton G.
    - General, 1912-61, undated (Box 114, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1887-1949, undated (Box 114, Folder 16)
- Photographs and Visual Images
  - Family
    - Beecher family: photographs and statue, undated (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Beecher, Lyman: photograph of portrait by James Henry Beard, undated (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Buffum, Relief (Everett) [Mrs. John]: photograph, undated (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Clarke, Rufus and Mary (Bassett) [parents of Harriet (Clarke) Westcott]: photographs, undated (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Diederich, Sybil (Hale) [daughter of Arthur Hale]: photographs, 1905, undated (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Everett, Alexander Hill, 1790-1847 [brother of Sarah PE Hale]: photographs of portrait, undated (Box 115, Folder 6)
    - Everett, Edward 1794-1865 [brother of Sarah PE Hale]: photograph, print, print of the library at his Boston house, undated (Box 115, Folder 7)
    - Everett, John (Box 115, Folder 8)
      [See Daguerreotypes and cased images]
    - Everett, William, 1839-1910 [son of Edward Everett]: photographs, undated (Box 115, Folder 9)
    - Hale, Arthur: photographs, 1879, 1884, undated (Box 115, Folder 10)
    - Hale, Camilla (Conner) [Mrs. Arthur]: photograph, undated (Box 115, Folder 11)
    - Hale, Charles: photographs, print, 1865?, 1868, undated (Box 115, Folder 12)
    - Hale, Charles Alexander: photographs, undated (Box 115, Folder 13)
    - Hale, Christopher Rose: photographs, undated (Box 115, Folder 14)
    - Hale, Edward Everett
      - Photographs, alone, 1840s-1914 (most undated) (Box 115, Folder 15-18)
      - Photograph album, circa 1901 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      - Group photographs, undated (Box 116, Folder 2)
      - Photographs with his children and grandchildren, undated (Box 116, Folder 3)
      - Drawings, engravings, lithographs, 1904, 1909, undated (Box 116, Folder 4)
      - Photographs of bust and of statue in Boston Public Garden, undated (Box 116, Folder 5)
      - Calendar with photographs, undated (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - Hale, Edward Everett, Jr.: photographs, 1860s, undated (Box 116, Folder 7)
    - Hale, Ellen Day
      - Photographs, 1860s-1933, undated (Box 116, Folder 8)
      - Drawing and photograph of portrait by Margaret L. Bush-Brown, 1910 (Box 116, Folder 9)
    - Hale, Emily (Perkins): photographs, undated (Box 116, Folder 10)
    - Hale, Henry Kidder: photographs, 1871, undated (Box 116, Folder 11)
    - Hale, Herbert Dudley: photographs, undated (Box 116, Folder 12)
    - Hale, Herbert Dudley, Jr.: photographs, 1899, undated (Box 116, Folder 13)
    - Hale, Jane (Murcock) [Mrs. Enoch]: photograph, undated (Box 116, Folder 14)
    - Hale, John, 1748-1802 [brother of Enoch and Nathan the patriot]: photograph of portrait, undated (Box 116, Folder 15)
    - Hale, Laura (Hale): photograph, undated (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Hale, Lilian (Westcott)
      - Photographs, 1880s-1960s (Box 117, Folder 2-4)
      - Photographs with Nancy Hale and Mark Hardin(?), circa 1910-61 (Box 117, Folder 5)
      - Drawings, photographs of bust, 1946, undated (Box 117, Folder 6)
    - Hale, Lucretia Peabody: photographs, 1860s, undated (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - Hale, Margaret (Marquand) and Matty Brooks Brown: photograph, 1887 (Box 117, Folder 8)
    - Hale, Maurice Perkins: photographs, undated (Box 117, Folder 9)
    - Hale, Nathan, 1755-1776 ("the patriot"): photograph of statue by E.S. Woods, and bust, undated (Box 117, Folder 10)
    - Hale, Nathan, Sr.: photographs, print, undated (Box 117, Folder 11)
    - Hale, Nathan, Jr.: photographs, circa 1865, 1870, undated (Box 117, Folder 12)
    - Hale, Nathan (1930- ) [son of Nathan and Lillian (Boynton) Hale]: photographs, 1932-33 (Box 117, Folder 13)
    - Hale, Philip Leslie
      - Photographs, 1860s-1930s (Box 117, Folder 14-15)
      - Drawings, 1902, 1911, undated (Box 117, Folder 16)
    - Hale, Robert Beverly (1869-95): photographs, 1879-86, undated (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Hale, Sarah Everett: drawings and photographs of drawings, circa 1840, undated (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Hale, Sarah Preston (Everett): photographs, undated (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - Hale, Susan: photographs, 1860s-1908, undated (Box 118, Folder 4)
    - Hale group photographs
      - Children of Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) Hale
        - 1860s (Box 118, Folder 5)
        - With friends, 1880s (Box 118, Folder 6)
        - With friends: tintypes, 1880s (Box 118, Folder 7)
        - Miscellaneous, 1840s-1950s, undated (Box 118, Folder 8-9)
    - Hall, Sybella (Hale): photographs, 1875, undated (Box 118, Folder 10)
    - Hansell, Harriet Ann (Littell): photographs, 1915?-44, undated (Box 118, Folder 11)
    - Hooker, Mary (Perkins) and Sidney: photograph, 1897 (Box 118, Folder 12)
    - Littell, Anna (Westcott): photographs, 1879-1942, undated (Box 118, Folder 13)
    - Littell, Elton: photographs, undated (Box 118, Folder 14)
    - Noble, Elsa (Diederich): photographs, 1925-27, undated (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Perkins, Charles E.: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Perkins, Mrs. Edward with sons Henry and Edward: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Perkins, Frederick Beecher: photographs, undated (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Perkins, Mary Foote (Beecher) and Mabel Gilman: photographs, undated (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Stowe, Calvin and Charlie: photograph, engraving, undated (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Stowe, Harriet (Beecher): photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 7)
    - Thorne, Margaret (Hale) (1898-?): photographs, circa 1912, undated (Box 119, Folder 8)
    - Thorne, Margaret, Jr., and Gilbert: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 9)
    - Westcott family groups: photographs, 1870s-1918, undated (Box 119, Folder 10)
    - Westcott, Edward G.: photographs, 1898, undated (Box 119, Folder 11)
    - Westcott, Harriet (Clarke): photographs, 1862-circa 1930, undated (Box 119, Folder 12)
    - Westcott, Mary Dent: photographs, 1879, 1885, undated (Box 119, Folder 13)
  - Friends and associates
    - Arnold, Helen (Freeman): photographs, undated (Box 119, Folder 14)
    - Baxter, Molly (Upson): photographs and photograph of bust, 1910, undated (Box 119, Folder 15)
    - Bridgeman, Laura: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 16)
    - Burke, Mary (laundress, Dedham, MA): photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 17)
    - Butler, Theodore Earl, Alice (Monet), and children: photographs, 1906, undated (Box 119, Folder 18)
    - Chamberlain, Beatrice Mary: Christmas card with photograph, 1911 (Box 119, Folder 19)
    - Channing, W.H.: photograph of portrait, undated (Box 119, Folder 20)
    - Child, Lydia Maria: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 21)
    - Codman, Catherine: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 22)
    - Dickens, Charles: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 23)
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo: photograph, print, undated (Box 119, Folder 24)
    - Fairbanks, Charles Warren: photograph, 1905 (Box 119, Folder 25)
    - Freeman, Harriet E.: photograph, 1907 (Box 119, Folder 25a)
    - Fullum, Abel (Hale hired man for 2 generations): photographs, undated (Box 119, Folder 26)
    - Garrison, Charles, Margaret, and Robert Hale: photographs, 1896-97 (Box 119, Folder 27)
    - Garrison, William Lloyd: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 28)
    - Hawthorne, Nathaniel (?): photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 29)
    - Hedge, Rev. Dr.: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 30)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 31)
    - Hunt, William Morris: photographs, undated (Box 119, Folder 32)
    - James, Henry, Sr.: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 33)
    - Keller, Helen: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 34)
    - Kennedy, Bobby and FitzRoy: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 35)
    - Kennedy, Edith (Mrs. Albert): photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 36)
    - Kidder, Henry P.: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 37)
    - Knowlton, Helen M.: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 38)
    - Lagage, Bastien: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 39)
    - Lesley, Susan (Lyman) "the Lady from Philadelphia:" photographs and photograph of drawing, undated (Box 119, Folder 40)
    - Lincoln, Abraham: photograph, undated (Box 119, Folder 41)
    - Longfellow, Henry Wadworth and Samuel: photographs, lithograph, undated (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Loomis, Ellen and child: photograph, undated (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - Lowell, Charles Russell: print, from a crayon portrait by SW Rowse, undated (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - McIntyre, Ruth: photo, 1919 (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - Owen, Robert: print, undated (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Peabody, George: photograph, undated (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Quincy, Josiah (Harvard President): photograph, undated (Box 120, Folder 7)
    - Richards, Ellen Swallow: photographs, undated (Box 120, Folder 8)
    - Scudder, Horace E. [EEH's "double"]: photograph, 1896 (Box 120, Folder 9)
    - Thayer, William S.: photograph, 1866 (Box 120, Folder 10)
    - Tilden, Rev.: photograph, undated (Box 120, Folder 11)
    - White, Eliza Orne: photographs, undated (Box 120, Folder 12)
    - White, William O.: photograph, undated (Box 120, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous friends
      - General: photographs, 1892, undated (Box 120, Folder 14)
      - Friends of Charles Hale, most unidentified: photographs, 1892, undated (Box 120, Folder 15)
  - Places
    - Boston Daily Advertiser building: photograph, undated (Box 120, Folder 16)
    - "Charlieshope," Walnut St., Brookline, MA (home of Sarah P.E., Nathan, Jr., Susan, and Lucretia Hale): photograph, circa 1865 (Box 120, Folder 17)
    - Enoch Hale House, Westhampton, MA: photograph, circa 1880 (Box 120, Folder 18)
    - Folly Cove, Rockport/Gloucester, MA (summer home of Ellen Day Hale, Gabrielle Clements, Lilian (Westcott) Hale)
      - "The Thickets" (first house): photographs, 1934-36, undated (Box 120, Folder 19)
      - "Howlets": photographs, 1942-76, undated (Box 120, Folder 20)
    - Gravesites: photographs, 1988, undated (Box 120, Folder 21)
    - Hale-Bancroft House, Beverly, MA: photographs, 1900, undated (Box 120, Folder 22)
    - Hale House, Newbury, MA: photographs, undated (Box 120, Folder 23)
    - Hales Place, Tenterden, Kent, England: print, photographs, 1830, undated (Box 120, Folder 24)
    - Hartland Abbey, Devonshire, England (Stukeley Westcott family seat): postcards, print, undated (Box 120, Folder 25)
    - 39 Highland St., Roxbury, MA (home of Edward Everett Hale and family): photographs, postcards, 1895, 1905, undated (Box 120, Folder 26)
    - Matunuck, RI
      - Summer home of Edward Everett Hale: postcard, photographs, 1967, undated (Box 120, Folder 27)
      - "Camp Nathan Hale" (summer home of Nathan (1930- ) and Lillian (Boynton) Hale: postcards, photographs, 1967, undated (Box 120, Folder 28)